♪ In the not too distant
Future ♪
♪ Somewhere in time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson
And his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in a nasty place ♪
♪ They try to survive
The wrath of Pearl ♪
♪ Just an evil gal
Who wants to rule the world ♪
♪ From her castle below
She sets her sights above ♪
♪ Just to torture
All the captives ♪
♪ On the Satellite of Love ♪
Get me down!
♪ I’ll send him
Cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst I can find
La-la-la ♪
♪ He’ll have to sit
And watch them all ♪
♪ And I’ll monitor his mind
La-la-la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can’t control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin or end
la-la-la ♪
♪ He’ll try to keep
His sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
- Robot roll call, Cambot!
- You’re on!
- Gypsy!
- Oh, my stars!
- Tom Servo!
- Check me out!
- Croooow!
- I’m different!
♪ If you’re wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La-la-la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself ♪
♪ "It’s just a show
I should really just relax" ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
- Hi. Crow T. Robot here
on the satellite of love,
enjoying the great taste
and satisfaction
only smokeless tobacco
can bring.
Damn!
Just got to work
on my aim a little.
Doh, damn.
- Hey Crow, what’s up?
- Flavor, Mike.
Have a dip.
Try the Kodiak polar
ice melt menthol.
Damn.
- Crow, this is disgusting.
Look at this,
tobacco juice everywhere.
- Well, you’re just jealous
’cause I can enjoy full flavor
whenever I go.
Say, you need me to [indistinct]
or bring down a mule-deer?
- Ah, no.
Hey, which pop can is mine?
Do you know?
- Mmm-mmm.
Well, hell I don’t know.
Just jingle ’em all.
There’s a lot of satisfaction
in those cans, Mike.
Nah, you know.
I think I’ll just pass,
thanks.
- Well, I got a big load here.
Hang on.
Woah, heh heh.
Right down
into your shoe, Mike.
Heh.
- We’ll be right back.
- Oh, relax, Mike!
You just gotta learn to cope.
Bingo!
[♪♪♪]
[MOANING AND CHEWING]
- There, Mike.
I’ve clearly labeled them.
Now you don’t
have to worry about
accidentally
drinking my spittle.
- Man, have you guys tried
this Crow’s Tobacco
Juice Brand Pop?
It’s not that good.
- I’m gonna let Pearl talk
while I go vomit.
- Okay, alright.
- You know, the good stuff’s
on the bottom.
- Oh really?
- Okay Pearl, here we go.
[MOANS]
That’s it, that’s it.
You’ve got the power.
[CRIES OUT]
Okay, dig now.
Find it, find it.
[BEEPING]
[MOANS]
- Okay, home slice.
Time for me to inflict
some brilliantly cruel
experiment on you
and time for you to be
a helpless irredeemable moron.
- Well, okay-- Hey!
- This week, a variant
on Dr. Harry Harlow’s famous
maternal love deprivation
experiments on monkeys.
Only I don’t use monkeys.
I use you poor saps.
[GIGGLES]
And I begin withholding love...
now!
Heh?
How do you like them apples?
- Hmm.
No, it’s status quo up here
Pearl, sorry.
- Uh, uh, uh, Pearl?
I’m afraid the efficacy
of the experiment
depends on you
first administering love
and then later
withholding it.
- Oh.
So, alls I gotta do is
show them love first, huh?
Uh, okay,
love, love, love.
Is that where you find
the least common denominator
and then add the numerators?
- Uh, no. That would be adding
fractions, I’m afraid.
- Well, is it where
you melt the butter
and stir in the flour
and the salt,
adding eggs one at a time
in the sauce pan until...
- No, no, that’s your recipe for
puff pastry.
- Oh! I know what love is.
I saved some stuff.
- Coming up.
[SIGHS]
- This to me represents love.
Send it up, cream face.
- Love.
- Huh?
- Oh, huh.
So, this is Pearls love, huh?
- Oh, what do you know?
- Staple remover.
- Pawn shop receipt
for a 10-gauge shot gun.
- Wow.
- A bottle of Fleishman’s
lemon flavored gin.
- Yummy.
- Twelve hot pads.
- And an alternator.
Wow! Pearl really does love us.
[GIGGLES]
[LAUGHS]
No love!
Love is gone.
- Wow.
Heh-heh, so lost--
feeling panicky--
no sense of self--
developing stress disorder
and an inability
to work with others...
[GROANING IN PANIC]
- Pearl!
Please stop torturing Crow.
Give us your love back,
please!
- Wheeeee-ere is love?
- Oh, alright.
Here’s all my love back.
Just take it.
I don’t even care.
- And while you’re at it,
take a hug from the warm
and nurturing film,
The Blood Waters of Dr. Z.
- Love, love...
- Oh, here you go, yeah.
- Whoa, love!
- Here you go, kid.
- Sweet hot pad love.
- There you go.
- She does love me.
- Movie sign!
- Here we go!
- Goodbye, love.
MIKE:
Oh.
See, this is why I hate cats.
Look at this.
TOM:
Oh. Flood waters, huh?
Guess Dr. Z had a little
kidney problem.
[MIKE AND CROW GIGGLING]
[MIKE SIGHS]
CROW:
Uh, theme music?
Anything you want to
throw in at this point?
Eh?
TOM:
Guess not.
CROW:
Eh?
MIKE:
Thank you.
That was brilliant.
TOM:
Oh, I gotta go on a diet,
I can’t put it off
any longer.
[GROANS]
Dr. Z (Voice Over):
Sargassum, the weed of deceit.
TOM:
That’s what I smoke.
Dr. Z (VO):
Sargassum fish...
MIKE:
Sarcasm fish?
Dr. Z (VO):
...mighty hunter of the deep.
MIKE:
Oh, I’m such a great fish.
Dr. Z (VO):
What an inspiration,
you have been in my plot.
TOM:
Thank you.
If I get to sit here
and suck water
without you interrupting me.
Dr. Z (VO)
Your life of hiding, waiting,
stalking your prey...
CROW:
Ew, Michael Jackson skin.
MIKE:
Please enjoy a fish anus.
TOM:
Glaucoma and you.
Dr. Z (VO)
At just the right moment...
attack!
CROW:
Uh, I was gonna do that anyway.
I don’t need coaching.
MIKE:
Now... digest!
Dr. Z (VO)
I love you.
TOM: [LAUGHS]
And I love you,
but not in that way.
Dr. Z (VO)
CROW:
Uh, I hate it when a fish
goes down the wrong pipe.
Blah.
MIKE:
Well, that’s the last
of my kids.
Dr. Z (VO)
And my friend, the shark.
TOM:
Hi.
Dr. Z (VO)
Cunning, swift.
Wretched humans,
they’re afraid of you.
I admire you.
Soon, I’ll swim with you.
They’ll be afraid.
[LAUGHS]
TOM:
Well, that’s one
I tell for myself.
Dr. Z (VO)
Oh, mighty scorpion.
Dangerous beast of the ocean.
With your powerful daggers
and your camouflage,
you have little to fear
from other fish.
CROW:
Yeah, well you’re kinda
blowing my cover right now.
[LAUGHING]
MIKE:
What?
Dr. Z (VO)
They think I’m insane.
They’re the ones
who are insane!
Oh, my friends of the deep.
TOM:
Just tap some fish flakes in
and then leave.
Dr. Z (VO)
This day, this very day,
I’ll become one of you.
CROW:
Yeah, we’re really excited
about it down here.
MIKE: [IMITATING WEEPING]
Oh, no one will hug me.
Dr. Z (VO)
My family.
TOM:
And you, balding
comb over fish.
Dr. Z (VO)
And together,
we’ll conquer the universe.
CROW:
Or my one-room
basement apartment
I share with mother.
MIKE:
But first, a folk song
by Phil Ochs.
CROW:
It’s got playful
teen beach movie font.
TOM:
♪ Oh Dr. Z won’t you love me ♪
♪ In World War II boy ♪
MIKE:
Sounds like the indigo boys.
CROW:
Well, I guess I better
get back to world domination.
♪ For all the missing
With your luck ♪
TOM:
He doesn’t inspire
this kind of music.
♪ Keeps you up at night ♪
MIKE:
Where the hell is my house?
♪ Their moon tangles
Both your feet ♪
CROW:
This is the leakiest damn pool.
♪ Drags you down helplessly
Toward your fate ♪
MIKE: [IMITATING]
Well, that was fun.
♪ Tombstones are piling up
Your last mistake ♪
MIKE:
I should rotate my bodies,
I guess.
♪ Give us a break
Give us a break ♪
CROW:
Give us a break!
TOM:
Yeah, this is obviously
Switzerland.
MIKE:
My Sustical has made me
the dynamo I am today.
♪ Sashay sashay
Through the sarcasm ♪
CROW:
Oh, I’m really gonna sashay
through the sarcasm.
♪ ...skulking
Through the sarcasm ♪
♪ Planning revenge
On your friends ♪
MIKE:
Oh, I would never do that.
CROW:
Oh, go on with you.
TOM: [HUMMING]
Planning revenge on my friends.
[HUMMING]
MIKE:
Well, he’s got
an egg shaped head.
CROW:
That song put the boogie
in my feet.
MIKE:
He’s got
the Gwyneth Paltrow haircut.
TOM:
Should I perform
horrible experiments
or count my used tissues?
Dr. Z (VO)
The formula
they all laughed at
is Z sub A and A sub T.
My little gem.
Zapped!
[MIKE AND TOM YELL IN SURPRISE]
Dr. Z (VO)
Very powerful.
They have fish the size
they’ve never seen before,
walking fish...
CROW:
It’s making spray ketchup.
- ...who like human flesh.
MIKE:
Oh, I’ll just have
some vegetables.
TOM:
My walk-in toilet
is working out well.
CROW:
♪ I’m planning revenge
On my friends ♪
Dr. Z (VO)
Clarias batrachus,
the walking catfish.
Clarias has been
equipped by nature
to swim in water
or walk on land.
Clarias reproduce very rapidly
and spawn through
much of the year.
TOM:
Hey, who doesn’t?
Dr. Z (VO)
and its continued spread
poses a threat
to the fresh water ecology
of a wide area.
MIKE:
And they’re great
for the grill.
Dr. Z (VO)
Forward progress is made
with a snake-like slither
and a vigorous thrashing
of the tail.
CROW:
Like Courtney Love.
Dr. Z (VO)
Whisker like barbells
equipped with taste buds
rush along the bottom
in search of food.
The largest clarias
so far collected in Florida
is 18 inches.
TOM:
All stuff not to say
on your first date.
MIKE:
This guy peaked in the womb.
Dr. Z (VO)
We’re going to do
something about your size.
You can’t battle people
being just two feet long.
CROW:
Unless you’re Doug Flutie.
Dr. Z (VO)
You must be tired.
So am I.
It’s been a long 20 years.
TOM:
Well, it’s been
a long 20 minutes.
Dr. Z (VO)
But today, a new life
will start for me.
Oh, but you know that.
MIKE:
We do?
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Wow, the darts for that thing
must be huge.
CROW:
It’s his what shirt
should I wear wheel.
TOM:
So, all roads lead
to Wally Cox I guess.
MIKE:
Well, the smog fish
is off the roster.
He won’t be able
to pitch for a month.
CROW:
The B.O. Suite for bassoon.
Dr. Z (VO)
It won’t be long now.
Very soon the whole world will
know about us and respect us.
TOM:
Or they might not,
it’s hard to say.
CROW:
I need another
bowl of Zoloft.
TOM:
This is what pap-per-view
headquarters looks like.
MIKE:
Well, if you’re gonna live
in a basement,
you might as well have
all the bells and whistles.
CROW:
I should get to
canning those beets.
TOM:
I need to simplify
my masturbation ritual.
MIKE:
Oh, look up there.
He’s filed all his letters
to Gillian Anderson.
CROW:
He’s learned to modulate
his flatulence.
TOM:
Ew. [CHUCKLES]
Well, let’s see what’s on
the Sci-fi channel tonight.
MIKE:
Oh yeah.
That was a good sample.
Some of my best work.
CROW:
Well, I’d better change.
William and Pat Buckley
are coming over tonight.
TOM: [IMITATES CREEPY MUSIC]
Oh, yuck.
He’s got Leonardo DiCaprio
physique.
MIKE:
Must’ve bought the
James Stewart Workout tape.
TOM:
Heh-heh.
CROW:
Now, where does that go?
TOM:
Iggy Pop’s brother,
Steve Pop.
MIKE:
It’s from the Sid Vicious
Signature Series of needles.
TOM: [MAKES MACHINE NOISES]
Winona Ryder, trash her hotel,
maybe take a gun
on a plane.
MIKE:
Hey, we’re on the air in here!
CROW:
Yeah, I wish I’d
noticed this thing
before I bought the house.
TOM:
Mark McGwire before creatine.
MIKE:
Well, I hate to call
those things love handles,
but there they are.
CROW:
He’s been sculpted
out of belly skin.
MIKE:
He’s playing the calliope.
TOM: [IMITATES MACHINE NOISES]
I think this is the new iMac.
MIKE:
No, no! Not here.
CROW:
No! I’d rather see
Sammo Hung wearing a Speedo.
TOM:
Look away.
Oh man, he should go
to an underwear fitting clinic.
MIKE:
Oh, come on!
Lawn, tubes, fluid,
men in their underwear,
what’s next?
CROW:
Uh, he’s gonna try to win
Ben Stein’s money.
TOM: [IMITATES SINISTER LAUGH]
I’ve got the crab tree
[indistinct] bath beads
and I’m ready to soak.
MIKE:
Let’s see, I think
I got everything--
oh wait, nipple clamps,
that’s it.
CROW:
Eh, looks like the Guinness
Record Book people
aren’t gonna show up.
MIKE:
This is why I got kicked
off the swim team.
Everything was
such a big damn deal.
TOM: [IMITATE ANNOUNCER]
Now, performing
high above the bathtub.
CROW:
And self baptism
sweeps the nation!
TOM:
Gross, matted hair.
CROW:
Yeesh. Not much to adjust,
but still
it needs to be adjusted.
CROW:
Whoa!
TOM:
[CHUCKLES]
Rampart, rampart.
CROW:
George, are you planning
emergency in the bathroom?
TOM:
No mother!
Rampart...
MIKE:
Oh cold, oh cold, cold, cold...
CROW:
He’s finally
washing his shorts.
MIKE:
Why, it’s blackberry.
TOM:
Oh, he’s in here.
CROW:
Underwater photography
by Zapruder.
TOM:
I thought watching an aquarium
was supposed to be relaxing.
MIKE:
Oh, okay.
So, he’s a dumpy seahorse.
TOM:
Oh, rats.
I wanted to be a princess.
CROW:
Wow, they do have hard water.
MIKE:
Aw, he lost his boxer shorts.
- Nothing at all
like the catfish.
TOM:
I look a little
like Jenna Elfman.
- But it’s beautiful.
CROW:
Yeah, it’s great.
MIKE:
Well, it’s grandma.
Hi grandma.
TOM:
Now, I’m going to
Armor All my skin.
- And now,
another big challenge for you.
CROW:
Getting a cab
while wearing this thing.
MIKE:
Kinda weird when your monster
has to use a handrail.
TOM:
Now to get a bottle
of Bordeaux
and seduce a mollusk.
CROW:
Whoopsie!
MIKE:
You know, frankly I think
the world can handle
this invasion.
TOM:
I don’t want none unless
it’s got buns, hon.
MIKE:
Snake, the Don Prudhomme.
[TOM CHUCKLES]
CROW:
♪ I’m walking
yes indeed I’m walking ♪
MIKE:
Anyway, that big challenge?
Uh, we’ll be getting to that.
TOM:
Oh, I forgot my nose plug,
and water wings,
and my noodle.
CROW:
He’s just doing this
to avoid getting
a fishing license.
MIKE:
Aw, I just realized
that I have to go to the bottom
and suck mud.
TOM:
I’m gonna swim to Mississippi
to draw attention
to catfishism.
CROW:
Please, I hardly know you.
Get.
MIKE: [IMITATES CONGESTION]
Oh, oh, I’m really stuffed up.
Oh.
TOM:
Ah yes, the good old days
before sewage treatment.
CROW:
Now, run away octo-puss.
MIKE:
It’s polishing the sea.
TOM:
There’s a sushi chef
after me, help!
CROW:
I’m sorry, I really
stunk up the ocean.
MIKE:
You know, I still
get crappy reception.
TOM:
I think he’s the janitor
at Sea World.
[EVIL VOICE]
Saddle soap, cleaning
compound of deceit!
Shoe polishing human,
soon you will pay.
A life of cleaning,
scrubbing, polishing your shoe.
At just the right moment,
attack!
- Uh, can I help you, Crow?
[SINISTER LAUGH]
- How I loathe you.
- That’s nice.
[SINISTER LAUGH]
They think I’m insane!
They’re the ones
who are insane.
Soon there will be shoes
the size
they’ve never seen before!
Who-- who like human flesh.
And then, at just
the right moment, attack!
- Crow, come on down
from there.
- Sargassum.
- Would you just come down.
- Oh, I’ll come down,
you skulking biped.
But I am...
[GROANS]
[NORMAL VOICE]
I seem to have gotten wedged
in the bulkhead here.
[EVIL VOICE]
No matter, soon it will be you
who becomes wedged
in the bulkhead of my plan!
[NORMAL VOICE]
If uh-- you could just
give me a hand here, Mike.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
Hang on.
Let me see if I can...
[EVIL VOICE]
- Ah yes,
my friend the squeegee.
I love you.
[NORMAL VOICE]
Now if you could just
pry me out of here, Mike.
[CRIES OF FEAR]
Ahhhhh!
- Wow.
[EVIL VOICE]
Yes, now I am in many pieces.
But soon those pieces
will grow and grow.
- We’ll be right back.
- It is I
who will be right back,
to rule the universe!
Ow, ow.
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
So this is all-inclusive, huh?
TOM:
I’m gonna kill Marlon Brando.
- Biggest bunch of foolishness
I ever seen.
We had walking catfish
around here a long time.
CROW:
You got something caught
in your teeth there.
- Well, you’re the one
who reported it, Sheriff.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
Folks been bugging
the hell out of me.
But I didn’t want to make
no federal case
out of this thing.
- Not federal,
just state, remember?
- Yeah, the state of Florida
against a little
walking catfish.
Some case!
[LAUGHS]
- Just doing my job, Sheriff.
TOM:
Avoiding your drinking
fountains.
MIKE:
Bob, look.
Guh.
CROW:
Joe Don Baker and Basquiat
just hanging out together.
TOM:
Hey, don’t just leave
your crackers on the beach.
MIKE:
So, all this ’cause
he lost his boat key.
TOM:
Yeah, you’re a fish.
CROW:
Well, thanks for the nooner.
TOM:
How do fish do it?
I’m so cold.
MIKE:
I gotta be honest,
am I that much closer
to ruling the universe?
CROW:
Ow, ow.
I’m poking myself
with all my little Y bones.
Ow!
TOM:
Oh, now where did I
leave that towel?
MIKE:
Mom likes me to use
the side door.
"Oh, don’t get any scales
in the house."
I know mom, I know.
Leave me alone.
CROW:
So, I’m an amphibious warthog,
that’s pretty close.
TOM:
There, I’ve conquered Florida.
On to Southern Illinois.
Dr. Z (VO)
[indistinct]
your days are numbered.
MIKE:
You too, Richard Deacon.
COMPUTER:
Now listen to me carefully,
Leopold,
your theory
is too unrealistic.
I’ll have to insist you cease
all further experiments.
CROW:
Now, pull you pants up
and get out of my office.
TOM:
Fashion by Grinch of Whoville.
MIKE:
This would be a good place
for a standoff with the FBI.
CROW:
You still in your jammies?
TOM:
Jack Ruby at home.
- Don’t you have
anything better to do?
Like playing checkers
or arresting bootleggers?
- Nope.
And I ain’t going
nowhere near that office.
There’s too many
folks bitchin’.
Fish walking through their yards
and going in their houses
and garages.
But I told ’em
you had all the answers, boy.
MIKE:
Good thing my name is
Edward Boy.
- Well, at least I’m trying.
- Yeah, well I ain’t seen
that college education of yours
do us much good so far.
- Walking fish wasn’t
part of the curriculum.
They didn’t teach us how to be
kind to sheriffs either,
but I’m trying.
- You’d better be, boy.
CROW:
♪ I’m glad I’m not in
Dixie hurray hurray ♪
TOM:
He’s gonna tattoo a fish.
- Lou, I thought you said
that was a fresh water spring.
- I did, why?
Something the matter?
- There sure is.
There’s an extremely high
content of radioactive material.
- Yeah?
Well, what’s that mean?
- In your language...
MIKE:
Honkian...
- ...pollution.
TOM:
There’s nothing down here
I want to eat,
how do you do this?
CROW:
Purse your hood,
that’s right,
throw your top back, good.
MIKE:
Solo synchronized swimming.
TOM:
Uh, slug bug.
CROW [CHUCKLES]:
Come on.
I sense danger,
I better undress.
MIKE:
Man, this is so camp.
TOM:
Oh gee.
Oh great, and I just got
internal genitalia.
CROW:
I’m gonna paint my beer cozy.
MIKE:
Aw, I can’t believe
she’s using acrylic
for this landscape.
TOM:
Once I get Herby
out of the way,
she’ll be mine.
CROW:
Ah, I hope I don’t run into
that barren barracuda,
he’s mean!
TOM:
Wreath could use
a little lime away.
MIKE [GROANING]:
Can’t get to the bottom.
I’m a catfish
with too much body fat.
CROW:
Silly string doesn’t
work too well down here.
TOM:
Hey, hey, Louie,
I didn’t mean anything by it.
CROW:
You know, you really gotta
wonder about nature
sometimes, you guys.
I mean, do you guys
even like nature?
TOM:
Ehhh...
MIKE:
Oh, UPS man lost some packages.
TOM:
This must be where they get
the water for Dixie beer.
CROW:
Look at me, I’m Red October.
Ha-ha.
MIKE:
Listen to that,
this movie needs
a whole new exhaust system.
CROW:
Damn, he eluded me again.
TOM:
I’m glad we went here
instead of Disney World.
MIKE:
Hey, it’s Lou Reed!
CROW:
Rex Reed,
Jake Reed, Willis Reed...
MIKE:
Could you please
do that someplace else?
CROW:
Sure... Reed.
TOM:
Someone’s playing
manhole covers.
[MIKE IMITATES SOUNDTRACK]
[HUMS LAST PART
OF BASEBALL STADIUM THEME]
ALL:
Charge!
TOM:
Hey, get the gaff
I hooked to Dr. Z.
[SCREAMING]
CROW:
The fun loving guys
of potato lake
kept us amused the whole time.
[CROWD SCREAMING]
MIKE:
Why am I suddenly hungry
for a turtle?
CROW:
Oh wait there,
I’m gonna get the camera.
MIKE:
And... go.
[SCREAMING]
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Who’s hungry?
TOM:
He’s trying to teach
his wife to cast.
MIKE:
Mmm.
- Damn man, look at that.
Whatta ya make, that?
MIKE:
You could make human loaf.
- This is a little
out of my line, you know.
But that looks
like a claw mark.
- No, no, no.
Couldn’t be.
CROW:
Okay, it’s a hickey.
- How about a fish bite?
- No, I don’t think so.
Look at the size
of these marks.
- Yeah, but we drug him
out of the middle of the lake,
you know.
TOM:
Are you gentlemen here
to buy something?
- I’m not sure.
Let me get a flash of it,
then I’ll take
a sample of the tissue.
MIKE:
Oh, you need to Kleenex?
Why don’t you use that?
CROW:
Make ’em stop, Rob.
MONSTER:
Maxim,
enjoy the earth while you can.
TOM:
It’s last call.
COMPUTER:
I can authorize you
to purchase another supply
of mice or rats.
But a human guinea pig?
MIKE:
What’s that all about.
COMPUTER:
That’s a request
I must turn down.
CROW:
Signed, octopus.
MONSTER:
You underestimated me.
25 long years
of frustration and defeat.
TOM:
He got held back a lot.
MONSTER:
It was worth every minute.
Now I know it will work.
MIKE:
Just put him in the back
of mom’s station wagon.
- I’ll see you [indistinct].
- Sheriff,
Doctor Fugato said
that Mrs. Maxim mentioned
the word "monster."
- The woman’s in shock.
- Wait a minute, Sheriff,
I have another question.
- How would you account
for the marks
in the dead man’s body?
- I’d say
they were fish bites.
CROW:
Fish bites mother.
- ...between this monster
and the rash of virus cases
here in the hospital?
Could the water supply
be contaminated?
- Hell man,
I ain’t no scientist.
It’s probably
a bug going around.
TOM:
But what about
my mod pant suit?
MIKE:
Hmm.
Shoulda tied something
to the net, I guess.
MONSTER:
Nets are no longer for fish.
TOM:
Uh-huh.
MONSTER:
We may use them on you humans.
[indistinct]
TOM:
Nets are for-- aw, crap.
I’m all tangled
in that dust...
CROW:
Alright, this is the final net.
TOM:
I gotta finish this up,
then I gotta go kill
Farley Granger’s wife.
Hmm?
MIKE:
Whoa, I need Imodium,
I’ll tell you.
CROW:
His hydraulics are stuck.
TOM:
There’s something
horribly wrong here.
She’s not in her underwear!
[CROW SCOFFS]
MIKE:
He’s lying in wait for Pogo.
CROW:
I think she’s about to
smoke Newport,
"alive with pleasure."
MIKE:
Should I ask her out,
or should I...
attack!
[BARKING]
TOM:
Couple more barks, yeah?
Okay.
[BARKING]
Yeah, how’s that?
Okay, nice.
CROW:
A swamp that’s filled
with corn flakes.
TOM:
This is how
all my pictures turn out.
MIKE:
Buck Henry at home.
CROW:
Make me laugh, my little Marge.
MIKE:
I’m gonna do some
indoor fishing today,
it’s much safer.
TV:
[indistinct]
That’s right, I suppose
you know why I’m here.
TOM:
Typical male,
sitting in his chair,
playing with his rod.
TV:
Before I do the job though,
I would like to
put my mind at rest.
MIKE:
Damn, I’m hooked
on my own sock.
TV:
About what?
Were you in those woods
this morning?
Kill me,
you’ll never know, will you?
I guess I’ll never know.
CROW:
Dr. Walter pointy sideburns.
TOM:
His fate is irresistible,
they’re coming
right into the house!
MIKE:
Oh the tension...
on this reel
seems a little high.
TOM:
He shrewdly set out
a bowl of breading
for him to step right into.
MIKE:
Remember? When you flushed me
down the toilet, huh?
Do you remember that?
[SCREAMING]
CROW:
The faces of the fish
he’s wronged
flash before his eyes.
TOM:
Ironically, he just placed
an order to CaBellas.
MIKE:
Excuse me.
- Who?
TOM:
No, "hello."
- Yeah, send him in right away.
No Shirley, I don’t want
to talk to him anymore.
Now you tell him, to go home,
board up the place,
stay off the street
and off my...
CROW:
Hi, we’re astronauts
from a different film.
- ...just tell him to go away.
MIKE:
Joan Stafford hair.
- Sheriff, these are
the two INPIT agents
that I told you about.
Martha Walsh,
Walker Stevens.
- Hi.
- Did you take a look
at those marks?
- Lou, they’re identical
to the ones in the first victim.
[SIGHS]
- God.
TOM:
That really hurts.
- Man, what are they?
- What do you think, Walker?
- On the surface
it looks like an animal,
like a cat or an ape.
But this man was badly stunned
or burned by some chemical.
- So?
- So, it could be
from the fish family.
MIKE:
You know, the Bagotas.
- Now look here, Mister.
You trying to tell me
that these walking fish
are strong enough
now to kill somebody?
’Cause if you are,
I’m taking a long walk
right through that door.
- Now just hold on
a minute, Lou.
Walker has to look at
all possibilities.
Now, he’s come up with an idea
I think makes a lot of sense.
CROW:
Which is to get
out of this boring scene
and back to the hot woman
with the bikini.
TOM:
Man, I didn’t know
bras were so much work.
MIKE:
I think that’s Gunnar Nelson.
TOM:
Really?
CROW:
I’m gonna lay down
in the sun underwater.
TOM [SIGHS]:
I like this film now, of course.
CROW:
Yeah, it goes without saying.
TOM:
Mmm-hmm.
MIKE:
Wonder how many
diseases I just got?
CROW:
Brrr. She is gonna get fan mail
from some flounder.
MIKE:
Is there any reason
for any of this?
TOM:
Oh yes...
CROW:
Yes, yes, yes.
TOM:
Oh yes.
CROW:
It’s Andy Warhol’s, "Swimming."
MIKE:
Ah, there.
I think I’m ready
to swim the Channel.
TOM:
Yes, world domination.
Got a little distracted there.
Heh.
CROW:
Wish he’d go after
personal watercrafts instead.
MIKE:
Marco...
CROW:
Polo!
MIKE [UNDERWATER VOICE]:
Can’t you see
what I’m trying to tell you?
I love you.
TOM:
He’s just testing for his
junior life taking bath.
[SCREAMING]
MIKE:
It’s a cop-a-feel-a-cam.
- It’s just a little bit
farther up the road now.
CROW:
Where’s Ron,
the regular bus driver?
TOM:
Now, you’re sure we can
water-ski behind this thing?
MIKE:
Yeah, I never get
a gift basket like this.
TOM:
Touching up your roots
is complicated.
CROW:
Soundtrack by
the Alan Parsons Project.
TOM:
You know, I hear
they lost their funding.
MIKE:
Aw, that’s too bad.
[♪♪♪]
- Yeah, nothing like taking
the rest of the day off
to do a little fishing, eh?
- Yup, perfect day for orbiting
right above bass lake.
- Yup, yup, yup.
Hey, anyone else up
for another... [indistinct]
- Hey, good idea there, Mike,
using a hula popper.
- Yes, sir.
Look out, sonnies.
Hey Cambot, give me
rocket number nine, would ya?
- Yup, yup, yup, yup, yup.
- Well, good day for it.
- Yup!
Yup, yup, yup, yup.
- Whoa, whoa!
- Oh, looks like you got
something there, buddy.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
- Lose the drag there, Mike,
there you go.
- There you go, let her out
a little bit there, oh yeah.
That’s the way,
that’s the way.
- Ooo, that’s good, that’s good,
let ’em tire himself out.
- Oh, oh, careful, don’t let him
go around the motor there.
No, no, no.
Yup, looks like you
almost got him there, Mike.
- Uh, any time there, Nelson.
- He’s a fighter.
- Oh yeah.
Wup, wup.
Any old time.
[SIGHS]
- That’s a long way.
[GROANS]
- Whoa, oh.
- Ooooh nelly.
What kind of lure
were you using there, Mike,
a grenade, or...
- Well, sometimes when you
bring ’em through high orbit,
they’ll freeze and go through
explosive decompression.
- Oh, that’ll
wreck your catch.
Better throw it back.
- Yeah.
- Yup.
- Yup, yup.
- Let’s give him a chance.
There you go buddy.
- Sure was a beaut though.
Must’ve been 30, 60 pounds?
- Yup.
Would’ve looked good
above the fireplace.
- Oh yeah.
- So, want to head
over by round lake,
see what they’re
biting on there?
- Yeah, that sounds
pretty good...
[BUZZER]
Oh!
Let’s reel ’em up there,
fellers,
we got movie sign there.
- Okay, real good then.
- Okay.
TOM:
Great, I have no thumb.
Now what do I do?
- Greg, secure that right there.
- Right.
MIKE:
I think they misunderstand
beach volley ball.
- Walker?
TOM:
You walk her, I’m busy.
- That report
from headquarters came in.
- What’d they say?
- They had several theories
on fish mutations.
One is
that the walking catfish
came over in ships,
quite by accident,
from South Africa
some 15 years ago.
The other is that
a radioactive material
from a nearby lab
may have caused
chemical reaction in the water.
- There’s a strange pollutant
in these waters,
that’s for sure.
’Cause I found it.
CROW:
Okay, I provided it.
- I suppose a mutating fish
could come over
on a boat from Africa.
They have any further comments
on their large aspects.
- No, nothing.
TOM:
Great, I just ripped
another jumpsuit.
- Why would he
suddenly turn killer?
MIKE:
I’m gonna be swimming over you
in just a minute,
just so you know.
[MOANS]
TOM: Hmm?
CROW:
Hey, you’re lucky.
Most fish think you’re ugly.
TOM [HUMMING]:
Hmm?
Oh great,
what did I step in?
CROW:
Am I missing something?
Is there fur on catfish?
MIKE:
Well, I got time for a frogurt.
CROW:
Man, bad install
job on a stereo.
TOM:
We’ll set
just the right mood here.
[CHUCKLES]
[SCREAMING]
MIKE:
Yeah, I know.
I get that a lot.
CROW:
He’s injecting her
with Murphy’s Oil Soap.
MIKE:
This is most peoples’ idea
of going to the dentist.
CROW:
The woman I tied in my cage?
She likes me.
MIKE:
Ugh.
TOM:
Didn’t blend her blush
very well, hmm?
MIKE:
Okay, got the girl,
got the keg--
Oh, we need a bag of chips.
TOM:
He’s wearing
a Betty Rubble skirt.
CROW:
Okay, scooch over.
MIKE:
Pretty good
with block and tackle
for a guy that only has fins.
TOM:
People in the south
have some odd courting rituals.
MIKE:
I’ll say.
[SCREAMING]
CROW:
I can’t believe
he’s going to dump her.
MIKE:
Just like Bela Lugosi,
he’s creating
a rice of pipple.
TOM:
Oh.
CROW:
Suddenly her Volkswagen
crashes through the wall,
her dog at the wheel.
[BELL RINGING]
TOM:
Okay class,
put your dissection trays
in your desk before you go.
CROW:
Oh, he’s just
lightly poaching her.
[TOM HUMMING]
MIKE:
Ahhh! Uh-oh.
CROW:
Umm, don’t call me.
TOM:
Oh, for the love of-- oh God.
Son of a-- Jesus--
Son of a-- gah...
CROW:
How do I turn off
that damned bell!
MIKE:
Yeah, sure.
Blame it
on the pinball machine.
TOM:
One little setback
and he falls apart.
CROW:
A poor catfish
blames his tools.
MIKE:
Hmm, Daria looks nice
without her glasses.
TOM:
I mean, Mike, you’ve had
victims die prematurely
but you never behave
petulantly like this.
[MIKE MUMBLES]
- I’m going to turn in, okay?
- I’m already turned in.
- I’m gonna stay up a while
and keep an eye on the detector.
TOM:
You women and black guys
need your sleep.
Us white guys are fine.
[ALARM]
- That’s what
we’ve been waiting for.
Come on, Rex.
CROW:
Follow my whiteness .
- Come on, Rex, it’s big.
MIKE:
Someone’s got
a Wagner soundtrack .
TOM:
They filmed this with
a disposable camera.
[HUMS]
CROW:
Net lines can get
tangled too easily .
Your insurance needs
can get tangled up too,
unless you have
Mutual of Omaha.
MIKE:
Hey, come on.
My kidnapped bikini lady
just died on me,
I got enough to deal with.
CROW:
If carp had pockets,
I coulda brought my leather man
and been right out of this.
MIKE:
Oh sorry.
Just saw the great minnow,
I really wanted to have it.
- You all right?
Go down there and see
if he went through the net.
TOM:
Uh, yeah. I don’t have to
go down and see.
He did, he did. Yeah.
- Don’t see him down here.
MIKE:
Still, it’s fun
just to hook one, huh?
CROW:
Well, I’m going to bed then.
- He’s gone,
you know that?
TOM:
What’s with the net ya dink?
MIKE:
You moistened my dry look.
[GROWLING]
CROW:
Alright, party of catfish,
I command you to attack!
[GROWLING]
TOM:
He’s unplugging him.
MIKE:
Throw him some coleslaw
or lemon, he’ll run.
TOM:
Poor dope, routinely
smacked around by fish.
[GROWLING]
MIKE:
Remember, I will conquer...
[GROANS]
CROW:
Man, there’s a whole
bunch of stuff
I can’t cross off
my wheel chart now.
TOM:
I’m gonna hide out
in the school basement
for the whole Christmas break.
[CRIES]
CROW:
This scene, lit by
a glow in the dark super ball.
MIKE [GROANS]:
I lost most of my surface
mucus on that trip.
[GROANS]
CROW:
I’m a failure as a fish.
I’m gonna try being a fungus.
TOM:
It’s okay, just a setback.
It’s my world to lose
at this point, it’s in the bag.
MIKE:
I’m just gonna watch TV
and eat some chum.
MONSTER:
I will cause underwater life
to triumph over
all other living creatures.
TOM:
Uh-huh.
MONSTER:
I will adapt myself
to a permanent
underwater environment.
CROW:
Next week.
MONSTER:
All other humans
will be conquered.
[TOM GIGGLES]
MONSTER:
I cannot, I will not,
be stopped.
TOM:
Yeah, you’re a real juggernaut.
NARRATOR:
I will select a mate
with utmost care
and together we will create
a new aquatic race.
MIKE:
Yup, rise of pipple.
TOM:
Rise of pipple.
COMPUTER:
But there is no time left.
CROW:
His head is paper mache
done over a gasmask.
[SCREAMING]
TOM:
He’s listening to
"Love Rollercoaster."
[CROW HUMMING
"LOVE ROLLERCOASTER"]
MIKE:
It’s the Uncle Fester alarm.
TOM:
He’s flashing back to when
he was at that other machine.
MIKE:
Yup, there’s where I blew it.
[BELL RINGING]
I gotta quit
beating myself up over this.
CROW:
Maybe I can conquer the world
through real estate instead.
TOM:
Hey, lay off the heavy music,
I’m just making a grocery list.
MIKE:
Onions, rice,
pizza rolls, tuna--
Oh, what am I saying?
TOM:
Better than the guy
that draws Sally Forth.
CROW:
Damn, sign says no monsters.
I’m gonna
have to turn around.
TOM:
Stop being nocturnal,
nothing’s open.
[FLUTE TRILLING]
MIKE:
Someone’s trilling.
I wonder if that’s
Lionel Trilling.
TOM:
Oh, shut up.
I’m hungry for real smelly
dough balls right now.
CROW:
When I take over the world,
I’m gonna put up
luxury town homes here!
MIKE:
Oh, I meant to trip there
by the lake.
CROW:
Yup, this is a catfish
you see walking, baby,
right here.
Yes, yes, that’s right.
Check out my fins.
TOM:
Think I’ll head
over to party beach
and see
how the horror is doing.
MIKE:
Oh, this is where he’s
"sashaying to the sarcasm."
TOM:
Ah.
CROW:
Ow! Cramping, cramping.
Ow.
MONSTER:
The pain!
TOM:
Jonathan Harris and Sue.
MIKE:
Oh, the chaffing catfish
right now, let me tell ya.
CROW:
I’m calling you out, Sheriff!
TOM:
Ching, ching.
[GROANING]
You know what they need
to take care of him?
Huh-huh?
Do you know, huh?
Do you know?
Catfish Hunter,
that’s who!
[LAUGHS]
CROW:
Hmm.
MIKE:
It doesn’t really work for me.
See, the guy changed his name.
CROW:
Yeah, yeah.
To catfish ChapStick.
So the joke
doesn’t work, Servo.
TOM:
That’s not the point,
it was a good joke.
Wordplay like that doesn’t
come around so often, you know?
MIKE:
Well, it only works
if you get the correct,
current name, so...
CROW:
Right.
MIKE:
...the joke doesn’t work.
CROW:
No.
He’s on the parade of homes.
MIKE:
Hey Tom, are you sulking?
TOM:
No!
MIKE:
Yes you are.
Look, look, I’m sorry
it was a good joke.
CROW:
No, no, it’s wasn’t Mike,
’cause his name
is catfish ChapStick...
MIKE:
Shhh!
God.
He’s suffered enough.
Open up,
it’s the fish police.
TOM:
Oh yeah, where the hell
do you get off?
MIKE:
It’s a good one.
CROW:
Man, a whole aisle devoted
to feminine products.
A whole shelf for swelling,
two for bloating...
TOM:
Uh, I need Gas-X right now.
MIKE:
Hmm, hmm. Go to cola...
well, there’s nothing
but freeze dried echinacea.
CROW:
That was locked,
but he now has the powerful
forearms of a catfish!
[TOM AND MIKE GIGGLING]
TOM:
I hate lemon swiss
cream flavor.
MIKE:
Aw, all they got is Clamato,
brown mustard
and martini olives.
CROW:
Damn carp proof caps!
TOM:
Label says, "Do not attempt
bottom feeding
on this medication."
MIKE:
Oh yes, thirst,
I will obey you.
TOM:
He’s hallucinating now.
CROW:
Ugh, seeing treble hooks, no!
And nets,
nets all over the place,
big ones made of
durable materials.
[CRIES OUT]
TOM:
So, this is while drugged, huh?
What’s the big damn deal?
MIKE:
Wow, he’s the Dana Plato
of catfishes.
TOM:
He’s too embarrassed to come in
and ask for condoms
when the store is open.
CROW:
I had such a pretty mind!
[TOM HUMMING]
Sorry!
MIKE:
Okay, I’ll give this
so-called heterosexuality
just one more try.
- Sue?
Don’t you stray away
from the house, now.
Call me at the hospital
if you need me.
- Okay, mom.
You be careful too.
- I’ll take good care
of her, Miss Pringle.
- I’m sure you will.
CROW:
Tonight, on invisible
cracker mom.
TOM:
Invisible cracker mom
and her invisible cracker car.
MIKE:
I wonder what mom looks like?
- Henry, are you scared?
- Nah, I don’t believe
in all that stuff.
Why’d any monster want to
come to this town anyway?
Come on.
CROW:
Let’s have an Alabama getaway.
[BARKING]
TOM:
I’m actually in favor
of this monster attack.
[BARKING]
- Oh my God, no!
MIKE:
Monster fights like
a third grader.
[BARKING]
CROW:
Hey, he pre-bloodied
his hand and hit the wall.
[BARKING]
[TOM SCOFFS]
MIKE:
Hey, nice.
I could see driving around
the country in one of these.
TOM:
Oh, monster love of mine,
at last I’ve...
- Rex, in the morning,
we’ll have Lou
take us over to the lab.
- Sounds good.
CROW:
Sounds great in fact.
- I think I’ll turn in
while it’s still quiet.
See you in the morning.
- Okay, pal.
Goodnight.
- Night, Rex.
- Okay patient,
time for you to bed down.
MIKE:
Let me unhook
your leisure bra.
- This is first class service.
CROW:
And yet I still feel compelled
to take a dump
on the drink cart.
- Don’t I get
a goodnight kiss?
- Anything to help
the patient’s recovery.
- Anything?
TOM:
The music’s swinging into
porn style soundtrack now.
Not that I’ve ever seen one,
so I don’t really know.
MIKE:
Uh-huh.
TOM:
Heh-heh.
MIKE:
Holy cow!
Can you do that?
- Say,
you’re recovering nicely.
TOM:
Nurses don’t do this anymore
thanks to managed care.
CROW:
Wet outer lip
squishing, yuck.
MIKE:
This is Fishman,
reminding you folks at home
to enjoy sex responsibly.
TOM:
You’re viewing his
digital camera slides.
Goodnight.
[LAUGHS]
- Yes, I’ve finished.
Go ahead.
MIKE:
Make your stupid movie.
- Sheriff, Sheriff.
This is the most sensational
story I’ve every covered.
A vampire eh? That’s what
it was, wasn’t it, Sheriff?
- Dale, I’ll meet you down
at Dee Hugh’s drug store, huh?
- Tell me Sheriff, do you plan
to call out the National Guard?
How else do you expect
to catch this monster?
- You know something, boy?
It’s a wonder that somebody
hasn’t stepped on you
and smashed you flat.
Now, if you keep bugging me,
I just might
take a notion to it.
TOM:
Can I ask a follow up?
CROW:
Someone dropped their Benyey.
MIKE:
Well, I can tell by
this pile of cocaine
that Lawrence Taylor was here.
- Damn!
As if we ain’t got
enough trouble around here.
- They’re the same wide tracks.
TOM:
White trash did he say?
- Web footed.
And those aren’t
human fingerprints either.
CROW:
On the bright side,
shower caps are on sale.
TOM:
Wow.
- But why would
a monster need drugs?
- For the same reason
he became a vampire last night.
To satisfy
some physical need or urge.
- But he’s just
an animal isn’t he?
- With human characteristics.
MIKE:
Is that hair or dog ears?
- Don’t you think
that’s pretty farfetched.
- No, Rex.
I’m convinced
he has intelligence,
and maybe that of
a human being.
Now we can follow these tracks,
I don’t think he’s too far away.
Come on, let’s go.
TOM:
I thought that was gravy, damn.
CROW:
I better alert my wife
to the shower cap sale.
TOM:
When do they get to go
to Switzerland?
MIKE:
Alright, time to
interview my hair.
TOM:
Audience, anything to say?
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Stage fright, huh?
- He’s gone in that direction.
- That’s toward
the Pringle house.
MIKE:
That’s where they slam a stack.
- ...killed that boy
right after he left here.
- Yeah, let’s get going.
TOM:
Quit playing Rat Patrol.
MIKE:
Gentleman, weeee.
TOM:
Mike, how come you don’t
look like this
in your jumpsuit.
CROW:
Are you sure you’re buying
the right kind of jumpsuit?
- KMB-3228 calling INPIT-007.
KMB32...
MIKE:
Now, let’s see if I can
remember how this works.
I’m a fish now,
so I have a real tiny brain.
CROW:
He has a moss caplet.
[BARKING]
I might have to door someone
at a moment’s notice.
- It happened up there
on the porch, by the swing.
MIKE:
That’s where you
were conceived, son.
TOM:
Boy died between
first and second base .
- Well, what’s the matter?
- Signal’s weak in here.
CROW:
Yeah, the movie’s
weak in here too.
TOM:
Someone’s pounding out
a message on a coffee can.
- Now it’s getting stronger.
MIKE:
The holding power of
my hairspray, that is.
- Come on,
he’s gone this way.
CROW:
It’s some kid with
a Fisher Price Bubble Mower.
MIKE:
Hurry up, now.
I got snake handling tonight.
VOICE ON RADIO:
Lab purchased by auction
by Kurt Johansson,
alias, Kurt Leopold,
employed at lab as
marine biologist,
radiologist,
14 February, 1941
through 11 January 1945...
TOM:
Und by the way,
♪ Tomorrow belongs to me ♪
VOICE ON RADIO:
MIT 1934, there worked
on radioactive effects
of marine mutations.
TOM:
Hogan!
VOICE ON RADIO:
Reportedly discovered
two new elements, zed-sub-A,
theta-sub-alpha and
A-sub-K, alpha-sub-theta.
And combined
the two elements
who are supposedly
highly stable
and would accelerate
biological mutations.
[MIKE HUMMING]
CROW:
My caddie stole my clubs
and ditched me.
[TOM HUMMING]
MIKE:
Figures they’d have
a white trash can.
TOM:
Oh well, I’ve been a brook
so long now
I can hardly remember--
oh, there I go babbling again.
[CHUCKLES]
VOICE ON RADIO:
Classified medical reports
indicate
Leopold mentally unstable
with paranoid tendencies.
Dismissed Doctor’s
repeated requests
for human guinea pigs
to test theories.
MIKE:
She’s tuned into
the German explaining station.
[TOM GIGGLES]
VOICE ON RADIO:
...that he would create
an underwater race
that would rule the world.
CROW [IMITATING GERMAN ACCENT]:
Back after this.
TOM:
Boy, it’s all
coming together now.
Yeah.
MIKE:
I just love driving around
looking at houses with you.
My Todd won’t go
anywhere near one.
Oh, that one’s nice.
CROW:
You guys, I got a frog.
TOM:
Ah, just let him go.
He wasn’t contributing much
to the movie anyway.
- Come on, let’s go.
MIKE:
I’m not speaking to you.
- What’s the matter, Lou?
- A human fish.
CROW:
That’s what I married.
- Sounds like something
old Doc Leopold might try.
He was known as a nut.
Folks laughed at him.
Said he was once
trying to get volunteers
off death row and prison
to try experiments on.
- Is that for real, Lou?
- Yeah, there was a rumor
going around
that he was trying to...
- To what?
- ...turn a man into a fish.
- Damn, Lou!
Why didn’t you tell us sooner?
- Well, I never thought it
until just this second.
ALL:
Mmm, yeah, err...
- Let’s get moving then.
TOM:
Ah, finally back
to the movie.
CROW:
Tom, you take the mirror,
I’ll watch the back.
TOM:
Right, okay.
CROW:
Nude.
TOM:
Oh yes.
MIKE:
Dum de dum dum.
Man, am I lucky.
Whoa.
- You kids sure
were lucky that night.
- Yeah, you sure
as hells were.
TOM:
Now they’re at
the governor’s mansion.
- Rex, take a note of this.
- Looks like
at each of these places,
he hits
in an easterly direction.
- Do you think
he’s headed toward the ocean?
MIKE:
Well, he had his trunks on.
- Could be.
- Now, if he’s a fish,
how long can he stay
out of water?
CROW:
Not as long as Michael Stipe.
- I think he’s headed
towards water right now.
Let’s go.
MIKE:
You know, it’s hard to keep
my chunky torso balanced
on my chicken legs.
TOM:
You seem kinda mad at me
for not remembering
the weird fish doctor before.
CROW:
Larry?
Larry, we’re over here.
TOM:
So, what happened
to the nude lady.
MIKE:
There was no nude lady.
TOM:
Exactly my point, Mike.
- I just don’t get it, Mike.
You seem so reasonable
most of the time.
- And yet,
you refuse to concede
that most scenes in most movies
would be far better...
- More interesting
with more subtext
and the emotional weight...
- If the actors were nude.
- I’m sorry,
I just can’t accept that.
[SIGHS]
- Brain Guy, Bobo,
we need you.
[COUNTRY MUSIC]
- Yeah?
- We’re having that same problem
with Mike again.
Could you help us
prove to him
that any scene
is played better nude.
- Oh, sure.
Have something from
Glengarry Glen Ross perhaps?
- Sounds good.
- Sales meeting, or that scene
between Shelly and Moss.
- Aw, either one.
- Hey, hey wait a minute.
Don’t I get to see
the scene not nude first?
You know,
I mean with clothes on?
- Mike, what is your deal?
Everyone has to have clothes
on all the time, boy!
- Just go ahead, you guys.
- Okay.
[CLEARING THROATS]
- Mum-mum-mum, ha.
- So, you’re saying
you gotta go in there and...
- You.
- I’m sorry?
- Me?
- You have to go in.
You have to get the leads.
- I do?
- And scene.
Is there anything else
you’d like us to do, nude?
- Uh, no.
That was fine.
Thank you.
So Mike,
are you convinced?
- Frankly, no.
- Well Crow,
maybe that wasn’t the scene
to convince a nude skeptic.
I mean, it was good,
and they were nude...
- You know, isn’t it
just possible, you guys,
that what you really
want to see is nude women?
- Oooooh.
Maybe, yeah!
[LAUGHS]
- Um, hey, Pearl.
- No, no!
She’ll kill us, no, no.
- We just want to ask her
if she’d be nu...
- No! No, no, no.
We’ll be right back
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
There. Oh rats.
Where’s my hair bleach recipe?
MIKE:
Honey, I’m gonna mow the lawn!
CROW:
How come I can’t get
the internet on this thing?
TOM:
Look, I’m sorry I let one,
but can I please
ride in the truck now?
- Wait. Hold it.
MIKE:
I’m gonna make angels
in the snow.
CROW:
Hmm, I thought
I saw a penny here.
TOM:
I’ll be just a sec, don’t look!
- Meet me up the road.
MIKE:
Huh? Who said that?
CROW:
Oh, I’m sorry.
I thought this was
Julie’s apartment.
[SCREAMING]
TOM:
Screaming won’t mask
our problems, Agnes.
[SCREAMING]
CROW:
Just tell me
where your krill is.
[SCREAMING]
MIKE:
Oh, look at that TV.
Early picture in picture.
TOM:
Ah, Orangina will stop him.
CROW:
You know,
that’s the thing about women.
You pick them up
and they instantly faint.
MIKE:
That’s why they don’t make
very good
professional wrestlers.
[TOM HUMMING WITH SOUNDTRACK]
You are going to help me rack,
young lady.
CROW:
Suddenly, in
sepia tone-ville...
- Sheriff, these tracks
lead into the water right here.
MIKE:
Let’s see
what the Captain Crunch
treasure map says.
- He had to walk out
on the other side
because this lake
isn’t connected to the...
[indistinct]
- So, we’ll scout
the perimeter.
- Right.
I’ll meet you both around
on the other side.
TOM:
They’ll never see me again.
[CHUCKLES]
CROW:
He’ll never see us again.
[CHUCKLES]
MIKE:
Sorry about the noise.
I use wax paper
for underpants.
TOM:
Are we a buddy cop team
overcoming
our racial differences,
even making light of them,
so as to fight crime
in a small southern town?
I can’t tell.
MIKE:
His like need service
now lights coming on.
TOM:
Hey, where’d you guys go?
I thought
you were going to wait?
CROW:
The director who proves
there’s really no need
to ever end a shot.
MIKE:
Oh boy. Here comes a big tree.
They can just scrape him off.
- Come on, let’s go.
CROW:
Let me just get my standing
on the running board shoes.
- Martha?
- Be careful now,
he may still be here.
- He’s been here alright.
TOM:
Well, that’s not my point.
MIKE:
Oh great. She’s not here
and she’s clothed.
- Well, she’s not here.
- One of us
should have had enough sense
to stay there with her.
TOM:
Well, I was busy
on the running board.
- Sheriff?
- As of now, we’re all
going to forget
about trying to
capture this thing.
I want you to take Rex
to that lab on the double.
And Rex, see what
you can find out there.
I’m going trekking.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[TOM HUMMING]
MIKE:
I’ll go pick up
the other Banana Splits.
CROW:
No matter how much the movie
insists that there’s tension,
I must respectfully
disagree with it.
TOM:
Feegle, Bingo, Drooper,
Snork, they’re cops.
MIKE:
I gotta get back to camp snoopy
and connect this to a ride.
TOM:
Hey, doh!
What the hell
did I do that for?
CROW:
Real stories of
the Florida DNR.
TOM:
Eh, you know, these two driving
is starting to lose the impact
they were hoping for.
MIKE:
At least he’s nude Crow.
CROW:
You gotta point there, Mike.
Let me see
if I can enjoy that.
Hmm. No.
TOM:
I don’t know
where I’m gonna put her.
I already got
five of these at home.
MIKE:
Help, can you bullheads
give me a push?
CROW:
Geez, you pay 80 bucks
for a thing
and you figure--
aw, man.
TOM:
Um, where are we going?
CROW:
Sure, you thought the clown car
would solve everything,
didn’t you?
MIKE:
You know,
any car labeled "Hasbro"
is probably not very good.
TOM:
Stupid thing,
I’m gonna go get a pocket
or mechanics card that floats
in a cushion of air.
CROW:
Well, I’m gonna have to
put you down.
TOM:
Up yours, car.
MIKE:
Don’t drop her, those things
weigh a ton
when you get ’em wet.
CROW:
Oops, I think we’re
out of the scene, Ed.
Yeah, there you go.
TOM:
They’re visiting
the Billy Carter Museum.
MIKE:
I’ve always been curious
as to what the sign says.
Then we can get back
to the chase.
CROW:
He’ll be wearing leeched pants
by the time
he’s outta that swamp.
TOM:
Oh, Amos Moses was a Cajun?
He lived by himself
in the swamp.
MIKE:
You know what?
Sing Jerry Reed again
and I’ll crush you
to a fine powder.
TOM:
Okay.
MIKE:
Okay? Alright.
TOM: Sure thing.
CROW:
Thanks, Mike.
I hope you like your catfish
hot and spicy.
Chomp!
MIKE:
Not exactly
Belizaire the Cajun, is he?
TOM:
Oh, ow!
[CRYING AND MOANING]
MIKE:
I guess I could be stupider,
but it’d be hard.
- Check that out,
will you, huh?
CROW:
Their recycling looks good.
- Looks like a generator.
TOM:
Last time you said it looked
like a butterball turkey.
Would you make up your mind.
MIKE:
I gotta get a bus pass.
CROW:
Boy, when this chick faints,
she doesn’t fool around.
TOM:
Crap, I cut the wrong leg.
MIKE:
Wow, he trusted
his [indistinct] too much
and skipped a year.
CROW [WHISTLES]:
Nothing down here
but girly magazines
and empty beer bottles.
Oh wait,
this is my basement.
TOM:
That Nazi fish guy’s got
a real moisture problem.
MIKE:
The Nazi’s next project
is nailing up
some wainscoting
and putting in
a home theatre system.
CROW:
Deep inside the stomach
of chef Paul Prudhomme.
TOM:
Really m’am,
it’s around here somewhere.
MIKE:
Meantime, would you like me
to point out
some of the flora and fauna?
CROW:
I gotta stop buying
my jeans so tight.
TOM:
When do I get issued
a big wide hat Sheriff?
CROW:
And he falls into
a panther trap,
and he gets trapped
in a dumpster,
and then entangled
in a towel dispenser.
[TOM GROANING]
I could construct a crude yurt
out of my hair in which
to safely ensconce myself.
[GROANING]
MIKE:
Hey, it’s pick
your own lobster here.
- Yeah, whatta ya make of this?
- I don’t know. I’ve never seen
anything like this before.
CROW:
Gonna flood the market
with homemade consumme.
What a sicko.
TOM:
So we treat sewage at home,
where’s the harm in that?
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
Wow, man.
We knew he was
an escaped Nazi, but this!
- Hey Rex!
These pictures.
MIKE:
Think they might be evidence?
- There’s Julian and Maxim.
- These must be his victims.
CROW:
They’re autographed.
- Lou?
This looks like
a sketch of Martha.
- Martha? A victim?
But why?
CROW:
Why not?
- Damned if I know.
Human experimentation.
MIKE:
Want to try some?
- Lou? Get on your radio
and call Walker,
tell him
to get over here quick.
You can’t get him,
leave word with Dale.
- Right.
CROW:
Yeah, I got a word for
that human porketta.
TOM:
Now I gotta rash, aw.
MIKE:
What, what the hell is wrong
with my walkman?
CROW:
Wow, real Nazi.
Wait ’til I tell the wife.
TOM [GROANING]:
’Cept now I gotta
scorpion in my boots.
MIKE:
Dr. Z’s a strange guy,
but he writes
beautiful haikus.
CROW:
He should get a wagon
or a shopping cart.
MIKE:
Tim-- Timmy?
Timmy, give Daddy
back the camera.
Timmy...
TOM:
Quick, look like grass.
MIKE:
Ugh!
Well, I pulled my gun,
but I’m not going to use it.
CROW:
Go for the gills, man.
Go for the gills.
TOM:
Lambada, the Forbidden Fish.
MIKE:
Another damn blowhole.
CROW:
Did I just hear a fish
strangling a guy?
TOM:
And finally, he gets
eaten by a manatee.
CROW:
Ah, Outward Bound.
That’s Ryan,
I’ll see you guys later.
TOM: I’ll get you!
MIKE: Ah, come on!
TOM:
Well, it’s traditional to
carry you over the threshold
and I regurgitate
the traditional croup worms
into your mouth.
MIKE:
I was gonna take you
to Niagara Falls
for our honeymoon,
but it’s very difficult
to swim upstream there.
TOM:
Let’s see, "Dear Josef,
How’s Argentina?
Things are fine here.
Look out for Hess,
he has a screw loose."
Hmm.
MIKE:
This actually makes sense.
A race of fish people.
Of course.
CROW:
Now, let’s see.
What do you I have to eat?
Would you like some tetra?
TOM: [TO SOUND OF MACHINES]
♪ Yodel-ay-hee-hoo ♪
♪ Yodel yodel
Yodel-ay-hee-hoo ♪
- Canisters?
That’s it.
CROW:
I need to store my flour
in canisters!
- Mixed according to
the right formula,
correct proportions,
it can change a man into a fish
and mutate all sea life.
MIKE:
Mrs. Paul will pay billions
for this formula.
CROW:
There’s the toenail sculpture
he wrote about,
just like he said.
[SCREAMING]
MIKE:
The Beatles are on Ed Sullivan!
[SCREAMING]
CROW:
Now it’s Herman’s Hermits!
TOM:
Now, we thought
it would be funny
to bring our candid cameras
into Dr. Z’s laboratory.
MIKE:
So, you were in
for a prophylaxis
and turning into a fish, right?
CROW:
Why can’t I do this?
I’m all fins today.
TOM:
Shouldn’t she have chips
and coleslaw next to her?
MIKE:
Glub. Glub glub.
CROW:
I am gonna kick your fan, man!
TOM:
Yeah, yeah, come on
eight layer, come on.
MIKE:
No, possibly lethal
purple Herman.
TOM:
I gotta laugh,
it’s just funny.
Hoo hoo hoo!
MIKE:
Aw, sorry about the delay.
Another patient came in,
said it was an emergency.
CROW:
He’s striking the love
sexy album cover pose.
TOM:
Must... help...
save... universe...
got to--
Hey neat, I can see
what kind of lover
I am for a quarter.
CROW:
into a bivalve.
MIKE:
Oh, please don’t hit that.
It’s very delicate--
Oh well, let me tie her off.
I’ll come over there
and help you.
Hang on.
TOM:
I warn you, I’ve got batter
dipping in my back pockets.
CROW:
Here’s your percentage
of that net!
Ha-ha.
TOM:
This chick could grout out
the tub before I leave.
MIKE:
Just let me reel in my bloody
performance art towels.
TOM:
I’ve seen better fish suits
on sale at Montgomery Wards.
CROW:
This is the Gerald Ford
of monsters.
MIKE:
Thank goodness I had my
provolone carrying cases.
TOM:
He has to check his large
cheeses through customs.
CROW:
Anyone want the rest of
this pizza on my chest?
MIKE:
Waiter, there’s a girl
in my soup.
CROW:
I didn’t ask for
the undercoating.
TOM [YAWNS]:
Oh man, I just do not
want to get up.
[YAWNING]
MIKE:
I ain’t got time to bleed.
CROW:
Oh good, he’s pulling
the emergency stop
for the movie.
MIKE:
Watch out, there’s
a Wallenda on that rope.
TOM:
I will play Tarzan
once before I die.
CROW:
Gotta feed these giant
meal worms to my pet orca.
MIKE:
Oh, get spawned!
TOM:
The sure footed
mountain bachelor.
MIKE:
Can’t shoot straight.
My flared hands
keep catching the wind.
CROW:
That was a slip. I slipped!
MIKE:
But I was gonna be
the secret ingredient.
TOM:
The fiend was trying to
make canned lady stock.
CROW:
Oh no, did I faint
and get kidnapped
by a fish monster
with my contacts in?
MIKE:
Wow, dismounts not the
strongest part of the routine.
Man, I’m groggy.
I just watched
an hour of MSNBC.
CROW:
My oversized
shish-kabob protectors!
TOM:
Stop or I’ll stagger!
MIKE:
You know,
the whole catfish army
never amounted to much,
by the way.
TOM:
Yup, on the very
brink of victory,
ruling the world
seems to be slipping away.
CROW:
He expected
aerial catfish army support
that never came.
MIKE:
Great wide break on this curl,
and me
without my boogie board.
TOM:
♪ Baby baby baby
You’re out of time ♪
CROW:
Aw, geez. Ah, the hell with it.
TOM:
Yeah, this is what women look
like when they meet me.
CROW:
This guy’s got great weed.
- Martha?
MIKE:
a nice picture window,
you can see the ocean.
- Thank God
you’re alive, Martha.
CROW:
I need help getting
my dune buggy, Martha.
- Martha? Martha?
MIKE:
I’m busy.
- Martha!
MIKE:
Have a headache.
- Martha!
MIKE:
Get bent.
- Wait.
TOM:
And she’s in the end zone,
it’s been a great
fourth quarter turn around
for this woman.
- Martha!
MIKE:
If I had my little car,
you’d be in trouble.
CROW:
Hey Servo, wet clingy dress
coming up, yes yes!
TOM:
Yeah, that’s good.
CROW:
No, no, movie,
don’t - zoom in.
MIKE:
So, it’s ending like
an Italian neo-realist
movie form the 60s.
CROW:
She really shouldn’t go
with that weird doctor,
there’s a lot of fish
in the sea.
MIKE:
Oh God.
TOM:
This movie was the winner of
Cannes "Pound-a-huh" award.
Well Mike, I don’t know
why you’re so skeptical.
- Yes, I happen to think
the fish-man was
really onto something.
- I’m sorry
I just don’t see the need...
- Okay, okay, okay.
Just imagine, you’re boarding
a plane to Detroit
and you want to take
your honeydew melon along
as a carryon.
Are you gonna risk
having it mishandled
or crushed
in the overhead compartment.
No! But there’s no need to worry
with this handy lightweight
honeydew melon carrier.
- Okay, I think
I get the point.
- Or say you’re taking
scuba lessons in Baja
but you want to take
a tasty bunt cake down
for a mid-lesson pick-me-up.
Why risk a soggy salt water
drenched bake good
when you can simply pop it
in this attractive
and watertight bunt cake
carrying case?
- Yes, okay,
I think I get the...
- You’ve stayed up all night
making yourself
a delicious crown roast
for your lunch break
tomorrow.
And suddenly as you carry it
in your arms to work,
a freak storm
of basketball-sized hail
breaks out and rips
your carefully prepared
meat dish to shreds!
[CRYING]
You’d probably wished
you’d bought one of these
double reinforced
crown roast tote containers.
- Okay, I think
I get the point.
- You’re crawling on your belly
through the Philippine jungle.
Parched, snake-bitten
and near death!
But you don’t want to leave
your 20-foot-long
party sub behind...
- Oh hey,
Pearls calling, alright...
- The capicola,
the bread, the cotto salami,
the peperoncini
and the big sort of pimento
will still survive the trip
even if you do not!
As long as you...
- Nelson, nothing cranks up
my evil mad scientist thing
more than a good fish
monster movie.
Behold what I have wrought.
I give you the mer-monkey!
Using a giant [indistinct]
and my sewing kit,
I have created
a hideous monster
that will strike terror into
the hearts of seafaring men.
[LAUGHS]
And I’m sure you know I can do
something further with that.
- Rrrr, I be hearing a siren
song from ya far maiden.
- Harrumph.
- Arrr, I stand rejected.
- Not the effect I intended.
Bobo’s mermaidenhood
apparently attracts
lonely rugged sailormen.
[SINGING]
- Hmm.
Will now be testing on self.
Bobo, give me
that lower fish torso back.
- Okay.
[♪♪♪]
- Sargassum,
the weed of deceit.